Wade Gausden

0211101016 Dunedin wade.gausden@gmail.com LinkedIn - http://lnkd.in/TX JqB

Professional Profile

I'm an experienced software engineer with extensive experience in Microsoft technologies and working in the cloud (AWS and Azure). While my background is rooted in C# MVC/WebAPI web development, I've branched out to embrace other open source tooling. That includes use of NoSQL technologies like MongoDB and Elasticsearch, process tooling like Jira and GIT, and other technologies that allow for SOA/Microservices architecture.

My day to day work has been extremely varied in recent years. I'm a team player who isn't too concerned with titles or the role name on my contract, and more interested in doing what it takes for a team or project to succeed. This has meant I may have lead projects, architected solutions, or mentored other developers even if the title doesn't always match.

I'm someone that never stops learning, and I've been running a blog (https://dotnetcoretutorials.com) for several years, learning and then teaching about .NET Core. Writing has allowed me to work with developers as far flung as Nepal, and talk with developers from all walks of life.

Tech Skill Set

Web Technologies	Cloud Services	Database
C# Web API	AWS RDS	MongoDB
C# MVC	AWS EC2	MSSQL
C# ASP.net Core	AWS S3	PostgresSQL
AngularJS	Azure Websites	Entity Framework
HTML/CSS/Javascript	Azure Service Bus	NHibernate
Bootstrap	Azure Queues	Dapper
JQuery	Azure Blob Storage	
	Azure Roles (Classic)	
Other Technologies	CI/CD/Testing	Tooling
RabbitMQ	Teamcity	Git
EasyNetQ	Jenkins	Gitflow
Elasticsearch	Powershell	Github/Bitbucket
NEST	VSTS	TFS
Ninject/Unity/Autofac	NUnit/XUnit	VSO
New Relic/Raygun		

Work History

Software Engineer - Timely

March 2018 - Present

- Took a leap and moved to Dunedin, partly to escape the Auckland property bubble, partly to jump on board with an exciting SAAS company in Timely.
- Lead numerous mini-projects around code performance, utilizing APM tools such as New Relic and Raygun, benchmarking tools such as BenchmarkDotNet and ANTS Profiler, and SQL improvements using Azure SQL Performance

Tuner.

- Lead development on the internal API that services the IOS point of sale app.
 Including numerous architectural decisions to make the API more robust and extensible.
- Architected and lead a team to build an integration between Timely and Zapier.

Technical Lead - Provoke Solutions

April 2017 - March 2018

- My role at Provoke is a unique one where I split my time leading projects, fixing failing ones, and using my past product development experience to improve technical expertise and process within a bespoke software company.
- Technical Lead for a chat bot project for a large bank. Utilized Microsoft Bot Framework, Azure LUIS (Language Understanding Service), QnA Service, Sentiment Analysis, as well as various Azure compute/storage services.
- Technical Lead on a public web and customer self service portal build for a large utilities company. Built on the Kentico platform and hosted in Azure.

Contract .NET Software Engineer - wadegausden.com

September 2016 – April 2017

I decided to take a step away from permanent roles and take a look at the contract market. My primary reason was to taste roles outside of my Saas/Startup/Product background, and get a feeling for how enterprises, vendors and other types of companies work.

Contract Developer – Bartercard

February 2017 - April 2017

- 3 month contract to help build an online marketplace and credit ledger for Bartercard NZ/AUS.
- Build, modify and extend the NopCommerce platform in C# MVC.
- Introduce the concept of CI/CD pipelines using Atlassian Bamboo.
- Implement database migrations, deployments and database objects as code.
- (Try to) Implement scrum fundamentals such as a product backlog, daily standups, retrospectives, and release trains. Including concepts such as DoD, Product Owner and Scrum Master.

Contact Senior Developer – Geographical Business Solutions

December 2016 - February 2017

- 2 month contract to help build the web front end for a GIS farming solution.
- Mentor and help junior members get to grips with newer technologies such as task runners, AngularJS paradigms, the "Bootstrap grid", LESS.
- Built on ASP.net Core, AngularJS, Bootstrap, LESS and GULP.

Contract Lead Developer - Provoke Solutions

September 2016 – December 2016

- 3 month contract to lead a build of a SPA self service portal for Vector Power.
- Viewable at https://my.vector.co.nz
- Lead a team of 3 engineers and 1 QA.
- Built on a .net Microsoft stack utilizing Azure Websites, SQL, and VSO. Front end built in SASS and AngularJS.

Team Lead - Re-Leased

June 2016 - August 2016

- Hired to build a team in the Auckland office (Rest of development team was in Napier), but quickly found where the company thought it was and where it really was in terms of a satellite office were extremely far apart.
- Core role of C# development on a Microsoft stack.
- Heavily advocated the need for QA resource and the role that testers play in the SDLC
- Demonstrated ways to take a 1-2 month release cycle down to a single week (And move towards CI/CD).

Team Lead - Unleashed Software

June 2015 - June 2016

- Started as a Senior Engineer but very quickly moved into a Team Lead role working on Unleashed's Inventory Management SaaS product built primarily on a Microsoft stack (C# MVC, MSSQL, Angular)
- Stepped into Team Lead role to lead the "System Team". The System Team is tasked with the heavy lifting of moving to a cloud provider (AWS/Azure), setting patterns for working with new technologies (Elasticsearch, Azure services, NoSQL), and other core functionality such as billing and deployment.
- Moved legacy applications to better utilize Azure PaaS offerings such as Azure Service Bus, Storage Queues, Blobstorage and Web/Worker Roles.
- Lead the drive for better CI driven from Teamcity and attempted the move to use tooling such as Chef to give us more predictable deployments and environments.
- Provided direction for development processes such as branching strategy, deployment processes, and team building.

Senior Engineer - Findly

October 2013 - June 2015

- Senior engineer working on Findly's suite of candidate sourcing SaaS products built using C# Web API as a backend for SPAs, but with many other non Microsoft technologies supporting it.
- Worked extensively in cloud environments such as Azure and Amazon AWS
 (Including the migration from Azure to AWS). Utilized cloud technologies such as
 AWS EC2, AWS S3, AWS RDS, Azure Storage Queues and Azure Web/Worker Roles.
- Large use of NoSQL technologies such as MongoDB and Elasticsearch, alongside traditional relational databases such as Azure SQL and PostgresSQL.
- Part of the drive for better microservices architecture with single API's being used for mobile and web.

Software Developer - Bauer Media

May 2011 - October 2013

- Lead developer for Autotrader.co.nz. NZ's largest motoring classifieds site.
- Worked with the full .net stack utilizing C#, ASP.net MVC, Microsoft Server and MSSQL.
- Mixed front end and backend development with BA responsibilities such as requirements gathering.
- Managed the workload of a small team of up to 4 other developers. Including SVN branch management, ticket allocation, and deployments.

Freelance Web Developer - Various

September 2010 - May 2011

- Did freelance web development work in both MS and LAMP stacks.
- Mostly consisted of a 6 month contract with a syndicated content company working on their PHP sourcing engine.

Web Developer - Magnet Design

March 2010 - September 2010

- Custom web development for bespoke websites.
- Worked in the .net and PHP stack utilizing CMS platforms such as Umbraco and Wordpress.
- A great mix of frontend and backend development.

Education

Diploma in Distributed Software Development Ames Training

_ _ _ _

2009

Diploma in Systems Engineering Ames Training

2007